In the next few videos, we're gonna talk about how to construct LL1 parsing tables.
在接下来的几个视频中，我们将讨论如何构造LL1解析表。
And in this particular video, we're gonna begin by looking at how be build something
在这段特别的视频中，我们将从如何建造一些东西开始
called first sets. Before we get into the main topic of this video, which is
叫做第一盘。在我们进入这段视频的主要主题之前，
something called First Sets, we need to say a little bit about how we're going to
一个叫做第一组的东西，我们需要说一点关于我们将如何
construct parsing tables, or what the conditions are for constructing LL1
构造解析表，或者构造LL1的条件是什么
parsing tables. And so what we're interested in knowing, we're building a,
正在解析表。所以我们感兴趣的是，我们正在建造一个，
we're building a parsing table. And we want to know, for a given non terminal A.
我们正在构建一个解析表。我们想知道，对于给定的非终端A，
Kay, this is the leftmost non terminal. And a given input symbol, the next input
凯，这是最左边的非终点站。和给定的输入符号，下一个输入
symbol T, [cough]. We want to know what con-, under what conditions we will make
符号T，[咳嗽]。我们想知道在什么情况下，我们会做什么？
the move A goes to alpha. We'll replace A, the non terminal by the right hand side,
A步到了阿尔法。我们用右手边的非终结点A来代替，
alpha. Alright and that means that the entry, in th, the AT entry in the table
阿尔法。好的，这意味着表中的AT条目
would be Alpha and there are two situations in which we would like to do
将是Alpha，在两种情况下，我们希望
this. Alright? So the first one is if alpha can derive T in the first position,
这。好吗？所以第一个问题是，如果阿尔法可以在第一个位置导出T，
That means that beginning with alpha, there is some derivation, some sequence of
这意味着从阿尔法开始，有一些派生，一些序列
moves, could be zero or more moves, that will result in a T appearing in the first
移动，可以是零个或多个移动，这将导致T出现在第一个移动中
position of the string that's derived. And if there is such a derivation, then using
派生的字符串的位置。如果有这样的派生，则使用
the move, A goes to alpha, at this point, when T is the next input symbol, would be
在这一点上，当T是下一个输入符号时，移动A到阿尔法，将是
a good idea. Because then we would be able to match the T. Eventually, alpha could
好主意。因为那样我们就能匹配T。最终，阿尔法可以
generate the T, and then we'd be able to match the T, and then continue with our
生成T，然后我们就可以匹配T，然后继续我们的
parsing of the rest of the input. Alright, so in this situation, when alpha can
解析输入的睡觉。好的，在这种情况下，当阿尔法可以
generate a T in the first position, we say that T is an element of the first of
在第一个位置生成T，我们说T是
alpha. T is one of the things, there may be more things. But T is at least one of
阿尔法。这是其中的一件事，可能还有更多的事。但T至少是其中之一
the things that alpha can produce, in the very first position. One of the terminals,
阿尔法可以产生的东西，在第一个位置。其中一个终端，
I should say, that alpha can produce in the very first position. Now, there's
我应该说，阿尔法可以在第一个位置产生。现在，这里有
another situation, a slightly, more complicated situation, in which we might
另一种情况，一种稍微更复杂的情况，在这种情况下，我们可能
want to make the move, or we wou ld want to make the move, That if we see A as the
想要采取行动，否则我们就会采取行动，如果我们把A视为
leftmost non terminal, and T as the next input that we'd like to replace A by, A
最左边的非终端，T作为下一个输入，我们希望将A替换为A，A
goes to alpha. Alright? And the situation here that we're going to consider is what
去阿尔法。好吗？我们要考虑的情况是
if, alpha, cannot derive T? So alpha cannot, in any sequence of moves, derive
如果α不能导出T？因此，在任何一系列动作中，阿尔法都不能派生出
T. So, in fact, what does that mean? That means T is not. Gonna be in the first of
那么，事实上，这是什么意思呢？这意味着T不是。将会是第一个
alpha, okay? So, and our next input symbol is T. We're still looking at the situation
阿尔法，好吗？那么，我们的下一个输入符号是T。我们还在观察情况
where we have A as the leftmost non terminal, and T as the next input symbol.
其中A是最左边的非终端，T是下一个输入符号。
Now, This doesn't sound very promising. Because we have an input symbol T that we
现在，这听起来并不是很有希望。因为我们有一个输入符号T，我们
want to match And the leftmost non terminal that we've got, up next, that we
想要匹配和我们最左边的非终结点，接下来，我们
have to do a derivation for, can't generate the T. And so, but it turns out
必须对其进行推导，不能生成T，所以，结果是
that, this, that it's not hopeless. That we actually may still be able to parse the
那个，这个，那个不是没有希望的。我们实际上可能仍然能够解析
string, even in that situation, provided that alpha can go to epsilon. So if alpha
字符串，即使在这种情况下也是如此，前提是alpha可以转到epsilon。所以如果阿尔法
can derive epsilon, if alpha can go away completely, and we can basically erase the
可以导出ε，如果α可以完全消失，我们基本上可以擦除
alpha, then it could be that some other part of the grammar can come in and match
Alpha，那么可能是语法的某个其他部分可以进入并匹配
the T. Alright and so, in what situation would that be? Well, here are the
好的，那么，在什么情况下呢？好的，这就是
conditions. So, if A goes to Alpha as a production and alpha can go to epsilon via
条件。因此，如果A作为产品进入Alpha，而Alpha可以进入epsilon Via
zero or more moves. Alright, so alpha can eventually be completely wiped out.
零个或多个动作。好的，所以阿尔法最终可以被完全消灭。
Alright, and. If T can come immediately after A in the grammar, so there has to be
好的，还有。如果在语法中，T可以紧跟在A之后，那么一定有
a derivation for this to make sense, there should be a derivation where we are using
要让这个派生有意义，应该有一个派生，我们使用的地方应该有一个派生
the A, okay? With the A as an important piece of the derivation you know, from the
A，好吗？A作为派生的一个重要部分，你知道，从
start symbol. And what comes immediately after the A is the next input symbol that
开始符号。紧跟在A后面的是下一个输入符号
we are expecting. So in this situation, if we could get rid of the A, Then by having
我们在等着呢。所以在这种情况下，如果我们可以去掉A，那么通过
a go at the epsilon then we'll still be on track cuz potentially some other piece of
在ε上试一试，那么我们还会在轨道上，因为可能会有其他的一些碎片
grammar could come in and match the T. Alright. So in that case, we would say
语法可能会出现，并与T匹配。好的。所以在这种情况下，我们会说
what, what do we have to test for? What, under what conditions can we do it? Well
什么，我们要检测什么？什么，什么条件下才能做呢？井
we want to be able to do this if T can come after A in the grammar and we say
我们希望，如果在语法中，T可以在A之后，我们就能做到这一点
that T is in the follow of A. T is one of the things that can come after A in the
T在A之后，T是在A之后的事物之一
grammar. Now this is an important point, and a place where people sometimes get
语法。这是一个重要的观点，人们有时会在这个地方
confused and so I want to, to emphasize this, notice that. We are not talking
我很困惑，所以我想强调这一点，注意这一点。我们不是在说话
about A deriving T. A does not produce T. T appears in a derivation After A, okay?
关于A的派生，A不会产生T，T出现在A之后的派生中，好吗？
So the A and the T here it, it doesn't have anything to do with what A produces.
所以这里的A和T，和A产生的东西没有任何关系。
This has to do with where A can appear in derivations, alright? So if the T can come
这与A在派生中出现的位置有关，对吗？所以如果T能来
after the A in a derivation, then we say the T is in the follow of A. Right. So in
在派生中的A之后，我们说T跟在A的后面。所以在
this video we're gonna focus on, only this first part, the first sets. In the next
我们要关注的这段视频，只有第一部分，第一组。在接下来的时间里
video, we'll look at the follow sets, and then the video after that, we'll talk
视频，我们将看下面的场景，然后视频之后，我们将讨论
about how to put it all together to build this parcing table. [sound] All right,
关于如何把所有的东西放在一起来做这张餐桌。[声音]好的，
let's focus now on our main topic for this video, the computation of first sets. So
现在让我们来关注一下这个视频的主要话题，第一个集合的计算。所以
here, first of all, we have to have a definition of what a first set is. And so
在这里，首先，我们必须对什么是第一组有一个定义。因此，
we're going to say, for an arbitrary, string. This is actually, x here is a
我们会说，对于任意的字符串。这实际上是，x在这里是一个
string. Could be a ter-, could be a single terminal, it could be a single
字符串。可以是TER-，可以是单个终端，也可以是单个终端
non-terminal, or it could be a string of grammar symbol. All right, and if that If
非终止符，或者它可以是语法符号串。好的，如果这样的话
that X, can derive T in the first position through some sequence of moves, then we
那个X，可以通过一些动作序列在第一个位置导出T，然后我们
say that T, T is a terminal here, is in the first of X, okay? So all the possible
假设T，T是这里的终端，在X的第一个，好吗？所以所有可能的
terminals that can be derived in the first position will be in the first, of X Now
现在，可以在第一个位置派生的端子将位于X的第一个位置
For technical reasons that will become clear in a minute we also need to keep
出于技术上的原因，我们还需要保持
track of whether x can produce epsilon. Now so even though epsilon is not a
追踪x是否能产生ε。所以，尽管epsilon不是一个
terminal symbol, if x can go to epsilon be a zero or more steps then we'll say that
终端符号，如果x可以到ε是零或更多的步长，那么我们就说
epsilon is in the first of x and this turns out to be needed. We need to keep
Epsilon在x的第一个，这是需要的。我们需要保持
track of whether x whether things can produce epsilon in order to compute all
跟踪x是否可以产生ε，以便计算所有
the terminals that are in the first set of a given grammar symbol. Alright so now
在给定语法符号的第一组中的终端。好的，那么现在
here's a sketch of the algorithm. So first of all for any terminal symb ol the only
这是算法的草图。因此，首先，对于任何终端符号而言，
thing the terminals can produce are themselves. So every terminal symbol in
终端可以产生的东西就是它们自己。所以这里的每个端子符号
here I should just say T is the terminal. So for every terminal symbol, it is in,
这里我应该说T是终点站。所以对于每个端子符号，它都在，
it's first set just consists of a the site containing only that terminal. All right,
它的第一组只包含一个只包含该终端的站点。好的,
so now let's consider a non terminal X, okay so here X is a non terminal, and what
现在让我们考虑一个非终结点X，好的，这里X是一个非终结点，那么
it would be in the conditions when epsilon is in the first of X, well, if there's a
当ε在X的第一个位置时，它会处于这样的条件下，嗯，如果有一个
epsilon production, if X goes immediately to epsilon, then, obviously, X can produce
ε生产，如果X立即到ε生产，那么很明显，X可以生产
epsilon, epsilon should be in the first of X But also, if X can produce any other
Epsilon，epsilon应该在X的第一个，但如果X可以产生任何其他
right hand side Alright, Where everything on the right hand side can go to epsilon.
右手边好的，右手边的所有东西都可以到ε。
Well, then the whole right hand side can go to epsilon. So, in that case also
好的，那么整个右手边就可以到埃西隆了。那么在这样的情况下，也
epsilon is in the first of X. I noticed that this will only happen if this, it can
Epsilon在X的第一个，我注意到只有在这个，它可以的情况下，这种情况才会发生。
only, it can only potentially happen if all the EIS here are non-terminal symbols
只有当这里的所有EIS都是非终端符号时，才有可能发生这种情况
themselves. Obviously if there's any terminal symbols on the right hand side
他们自己。显然，如果右手边有任何端子符号
then that production can never go completely to the empty string. Okay. It
那么生产就永远不可能完全走到空的地步。好吧。它
will always produce at least that, that terminal But if every non-terminal. On the
总会产生至少那个，那个终端，但如果每个非终端。在
right-hand side can produce epsilon. Meaning epsilon's in the first of all
右手边可以产生ε。意思是epsilon在第一位
those non-terminals. And there are no terminals on the right hand side. Then,
那些非终结者。而且右手边没有终端。然后,
Then, epsilon will be in the first of X. Alright there's one other situation and
然后，epsilon会在X的第一个，好的，还有一个情况，
here's where we make use of the fact that we are keeping track of where epsilon can
在这里，我们利用了这样一个事实，即我们正在跟踪epsilon可以在哪里
be produced alright. So let's say that we have a production like this okay and let's
做好了就可以了。假设我们有这样一部作品，好的，让我们
say the first N symbols A1 through AN here can all go to epsilon. So this can all
假设前N个符号A1到An在这里都可以去epsilon。所以这一切都可以
disappear and can be replaced by the empty string. What does that mean, so if we have
消失，并可由空字符串替换。这是什么意思，所以如果我们有
derivation like this? Okay were, to some number of moves it goes to Alpha, well
像这样的推导吗？好的，对于一些动作，它是去阿尔法的，嗯
that means that X can through a bunch of moves here to derive Alpha itself, okay.
这意味着X可以在这里通过一系列动作来推导出Alpha本身，好的。
So, X will go to Alpha by wiping out all of the AIs, and I forgot to put the alpha
所以，X将通过清除所有的人工智能进入Alpha，而我忘了把Alpha
here on the end, there should be an Alpha after As have been there. Okay? And wh at
在这里的尽头，应该有一个阿尔法之后，就像已经在那里。好吧?以及在什么时候
does this mean? Well this means that anything that is in the first of alpha is
这是不是意味着？这意味着阿尔法的第一部分中的任何东西都是
going to also be in the first of X. All right? So, if any prefix of the right-hand
也会是X的第一个，好吗？所以，如果右手边的任何前缀
side can disappear then the remaining suffix, the alpha, it doesn't matter what
边可以消失，然后剩下的后缀，字母，不管是什么都无关紧要
the alpha is, is left. Then the first of alpha will be a subset of the non-terminal
阿尔法是，是左边。则阿尔法的第一个将是非终端的子集
on the right, left hand side of X in this case. All right? Okay? Alright. So that is
在这种情况下，在X的右手边，也就是左手边。好的?好吧?好的。那就是说
a definition of a first sets and how you compute them. Okay. And we have to, we
第一个集合的定义以及如何计算它们。好吧。我们必须这样做，我们
have to compute them for the terminals and for the non-terminals, alright? That's
必须为终端和非终端计算它们，好吗？那是
what these; these second two rolls here cover the non-terminals. I just noticed,
这些是什么；这里的第二个两卷盖的是非终端。我刚注意到，
as I mentioned here at the beginning that this is well defined for any other
正如我在开始时提到的，这对于任何其他
Grammar, sequence as well. I mean, excuse me, any other string in the grammar as
语法，顺序也一样。我是说，打扰一下，语法中有没有其他字符串
well. It doesn't, if I, if I know how to compute it for terminals, I know how to
井。它不是，如果我，如果我知道如何计算终端的它，我知道如何
compute it for non terminals. Then I can compute it for arbitrary strings in the
为非终端计算它。中的任意字符串计算它。
grammar, as well. Let's analyze, do an example. Let's take a look at this grammar
语法也一样。我们来分析一下，举个例子。让我们来看看这个语法
and let's see if we can compute the first sets. Let's start with the easy stuff.
让我们看看我们是否能计算出第一个集合。让我们从简单的事情开始吧。
Let's do the terminal symbols. Alright So, for the terminals, it's really, you know,
我们来做终端符号吧。好的，那么对于航站楼来说，真的，你知道，
extremely straightforward. The first of plus is plus. The first of times Is just
非常直截了当。加号的第一个是加号。第一个时代就是
times every terminal is in a, has its first set, the first set of every terminal
乘以每个终端在一个，有它的第一个集合，每个终端的第一个集合
is just the second term in that terminal and so on for the others, and this is not
只是该终端的第二个术语，对其他终端依此类推，这不是
worth writing out. So it'll be the first of open paren will just be open paren, the
值得写出来。所以这将是第一个开放的帕伦将只是开放的帕伦，
first of close paren will be just close paren and I think that is all. Now we have
首先，帕伦只会很接近，帕伦，我想仅此而已。现在我们有了
to do ants as well, okay? Alright, so these are the first sets for the terminal
也要做蚂蚁，好吗？好的，这是航站楼的第一组
symbols. And now let's look at something more interesting; let's talk about the
符号。现在让我们来看一些更有趣的事情，让我们来谈谈
first of the non terminal symbols. So What about the first of E? Well, if we look at
第一个非端子符号。那么E的第一个呢？嗯，如果我们看一下
the production for E, let's remember our rules. So we know that anything that's in
E的制作，让我们记住我们的规则。所以我们知道里面的任何东西
the first of T will also be in the first of E. So the first of T Is a subset of th
T的第一个也将位于E的第一个。因此，T的第一个是
e first of E. Okay so in order to know what the first of E is we have to know
E的第一个，好的，为了知道E的第一个是什么，我们必须知道
what the first of T is. At least to know part of the first of E we have to know the
T的第一个是什么。至少要知道第一个E的一部分，我们必须知道
first of T. So let's move on then to first computing. The first of T Let's, let's try
首先是T，那么让我们接着来看第一个计算。T的第一个让我们，让我们试一试
to get that set. Now the first of T is actually pretty easy because if we look at
才能拿到那套。现在T的第一个实际上非常简单，因为如果我们看一下
the productions for T we can see that they produce terminals in the first position.
T的乘积，我们可以看到它们产生第一个位置的终端。
All right? So the only possibility in the, the only possibilities in the first of T
好的?所以唯一的可能性在，唯一的可能性在第一个T
are open per en and int. And since there are only two productions for T and both of
是PEN和INT开放的。因为T只有两部作品，而且两部都是
them have a terminal in the very first position, there's no other terminal
他们在第一个位置有一个航站楼，没有其他的航站楼
symbols that could be produced in the first position by T. So we can just read
可以由T在第一个位置产生的符号，所以我们可以只读
off the first of T directly from the grammar. And it's the open paren in int.
直接从语法中去掉T的第一个。这是INT中的开场帕伦。
Okay? Now, let's return to thinking about the first of E. So remember there was
好吧?现在，让我们回过头来想一下E的第一个，所以请记住
another case that we need to keep track of. Or, sorry, that we have to consider.
又一个我们需要追踪的案子。或者，抱歉，这是我们必须考虑的。
So, it could be, or, clearly everything in the first of T is in the first of E and
所以它可能是，或者，很明显，所有T的第一个都在E的第一个，
we've already noted that down. But if T can go to epsilon then things that are in
我们已经把这一点记下来了。但是如果T可以到ε上，那么里面的东西
the first of X Could also be in the first of E. And now we've computed the first of
X的第一个也可能是E的第一个，现在我们已经计算了第一个
T and we see that epsilon is not in there. The first of T always generates at least
我们看到ε不在那里。T的第一个始终至少生成
one terminal symbol, and so there'll never be a situation in which X can contribute
一个终端符号，所以永远不会有X可以做出贡献的情况
to the first of E because T is always guaranteed to generate at least one
设置为E的第一个，因为T始终保证生成至少一个
terminal. So in fact this subset that we wrote up here is not a subset at all, it's
终点站。所以实际上我们在这里写的这个子集根本不是一个子集，它是
an inequality. The first of T and the first of E are equal. So the first of E is
一种不平等。T的第一个和E的第一个相等。所以E的第一个是
also open per rand and Nth. All right? So now let's take a look at the first of X.
也是按兰特和第N次开放的。好的?现在我们来看一下X的第一个。
Okay? So, the first effects well clearly pluses in the first of X because one
好吧?所以，第一个效应很明显加上X的第一个，因为1
production per X plus immediately in the first positions, so we must add plus to
每个X加上第一个位置的产量，所以我们必须加到
the first of X. And then X has an epsilon production so it can also go to epsilon so
第一个X，然后X有一个epsilon生产，所以它也可以去epsilon，所以
that means epsilon is also in the first of X And what about the first of Y. Well, the
这意味着epsilon也在X的第一位，那么Y的第一位呢？
fir st of Y, it's a similar structure to the productions request, we see we have
首先是Y，它的结构与生产要求相似，我们看到我们有
one production here in the [inaudible] of the terminal in the first position, and
在第一个位置的终端的[听不见的]这里制作一部作品，以及
that's times. So the first of y has times in it. And then, y also has an epsilon
这就是时代。所以第一个y是有时间的。然后，y也有一个ε
production. Y can go directly to epsilon, so epsilon is also in the first of y.
制作。可以直接到epsilon，所以epsilon也在y的第一个。
Alright? And that's actually it for this grammar. These are the complete first sets
好吗？实际上，这个语法就是这样。这些是完整的第一套
for all of the symbols of the grammar. The terminals just have themselves in their
所有的语法符号。航站楼里只有他们自己
first sets and then the non-terminals we computed have these sets. So that
首先是集合，然后是我们计算的非终端集合。所以
concludes our discussion of first sets and in the next video, we're going to take a
结束了我们对第一组的讨论，在下一个视频中，我们将
look at computing follow sets.
请看计算跟随集。